<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="faq.nestegg.eu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="faq.nestegg.eu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-12T14:02:04+00:00</updated><id>faq.nestegg.eu/</id><title type="html">NestEgg FAQ</title><subtitle>Answering FAQ about NestEgg.</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Track kWh</title><link href="faq.nestegg.eu/manage/track-kwh/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Track kWh" /><published>2018-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>faq.nestegg.eu/manage/track-kwh</id><content type="html" xml:base="faq.nestegg.eu/manage/track-kwh/">&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve participated in a crowdfund for a solar panel or windmill, you’ll recieve a share of kWh that it produces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;energy-history&quot;&gt;Energy History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media/kwh-history.png&quot; alt=&quot;Energy History&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though your infrastructure is deployed across the country, you have real time data coming from your devices that’s available for you 24/7. This makes your ownership more tangible, and allows you to monitor effects of sunny/cloudy days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;kWh past 24 Hours: the amount of kWh generated in the past 24 hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;€ past 24 Hours: the converted euro value of kWh generated in the past 24 hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Generated: the amount of kWh generated over its entire lifespan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Total Value: the converted euro value of kWh generated over its entire lifespan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Once you’ve participated in a crowdfund for a solar panel or windmill, you’ll recieve a share of kWh that it produces.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Join a Crowdfund</title><link href="faq.nestegg.eu/eggs/join-crowdfund/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Join a Crowdfund" /><published>2018-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>faq.nestegg.eu/eggs/join-crowdfund</id><content type="html" xml:base="faq.nestegg.eu/eggs/join-crowdfund/">&lt;p&gt;Join others in a crowdfund to deploy infrastructure. Together you’ll own the production of whatever it creates, such as kWh from solar panels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-your-project&quot;&gt;Finding your Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can browse available projects to see which meet your preferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/eggs/browse-eggs/&quot;&gt;Jump to: Browse Eggs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;payment&quot;&gt;Payment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose to pay whatever you want above the minimum. Unlike kickstarter, there’s no tiers or reward packages, you’ll be rewarded in proportion to your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, you can only make your purchase using iDeal, a dutch payment provider.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Join others in a crowdfund to deploy infrastructure. Together you’ll own the production of whatever it creates, such as kWh from solar panels.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Browse Eggs</title><link href="faq.nestegg.eu/eggs/browse-eggs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Browse Eggs" /><published>2018-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>faq.nestegg.eu/eggs/browse-eggs</id><content type="html" xml:base="faq.nestegg.eu/eggs/browse-eggs/">&lt;p&gt;To reduce your basic needs, you’ll start by browsing available crowdfunds for sustainable infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;browse-eggs&quot;&gt;Browse Eggs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When crowdfunds become available, you have the opportunity to help finance its deployment and purchase a share of ownership. This will increase your self-sufficiency by owning the production of various infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">To reduce your basic needs, you’ll start by browsing available crowdfunds for sustainable infrastructure.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Your Dashboard</title><link href="faq.nestegg.eu/account/dashboard/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your Dashboard" /><published>2018-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>faq.nestegg.eu/account/dashboard</id><content type="html" xml:base="faq.nestegg.eu/account/dashboard/">&lt;p&gt;NestEgg aims to provide you the portal to crowdfund sustainable infrastructrue and reduce your basic needs by owning the production. Your dashboard provides an overview of all the projects you own pieces of and your aggregated kWh generated from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- [Jump to: Adjust your self-sufficiency per industry.](/account/dashboard/) --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#egg-investments&quot;&gt;Jump to: Adjust your self-sufficiency per industry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-sufficiency&quot;&gt;Self Sufficiency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media/dash-self.png&quot; alt=&quot;Self-Sufficiency&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of NestEgg is to reduce your basic needs to 0 by owning enough production from a variety of sustainable infrastructure. Such as owning 10% in a solar panel across the country, to receive 10% of the kWh produced and directly reduce your energy bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your self-sufficiency bar can be set to your custom energy levels and will track the kWh produced from all your projects. This helps you track, at a glance, your progress towards reaching 100% self-sufficency, which means your projects would produce enough energy to reduce your energy bill to zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-eggs&quot;&gt;Your Eggs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media/dash-eggs.png&quot; alt=&quot;Your Eggs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The total of how much you have invested in all your eggs is at the center-top of your dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NestEgg calls infrastructure projects, “Eggs”. Thus, you can see how many projects (eggs) you have in your portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: this box doesn’t track the size of each share. Thus, 1% or 99% ownership of an egg would still be displayed as “1 Egg”. To dividend box tracks how much you receive each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dividend&quot;&gt;Dividend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media/dash-dividend.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dividend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you own shares in a variety of energy projects, they will each produce a portion of kWh. The dividend box aggregates all the kWh coming from your eggs each month, so you can track the euro equivalent of what your total investment creates each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;egg-investments&quot;&gt;Egg Investments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media/dash-investments.png&quot; alt=&quot;Industries&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here your projects are aggregated into their corresponding indsutry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⚡️ Energy projects provide kWh to reduce your energy bill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🚘 Transport projects provide free mobility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🖥 Leisure projects are usually expensive gadgets and equipment that allows individuals to have the same purchasing power as a company, providing access to enterprise tools at a literal fraction of the price.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🏡 Real Estate projects provide streams of rent and/or free credits to rent the location for a night.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🥕 Food Projects provide weekly shipments of produce produced on your plot of land&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you have suggestions, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto: info@nestegg.eu&quot;&gt;we welcome you to email us feedback&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;⚠ Currently, NestEgg only supports sustainable energy projects. We plan to cover other other basic needs over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within each industry, you view further information and settings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adjust your self-sufficiency needs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generation: the utility generated each moneth (example: kWh from your Energy projects)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cashed Out: how much utility you’ve sold for euro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bill Reduction: how much utility has reduced your energy bill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">NestEgg aims to provide you the portal to crowdfund sustainable infrastructrue and reduce your basic needs by owning the production. Your dashboard provides an overview of all the projects you own pieces of and your aggregated kWh generated from them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Register an Account</title><link href="faq.nestegg.eu/account/register/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Register an Account" /><published>2018-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>faq.nestegg.eu/account/register</id><content type="html" xml:base="faq.nestegg.eu/account/register/">&lt;p&gt;NestEgg aims to provide you the portal to crowdfund sustainable infrastructrue and reduce your basic needs by owning the production. The first step is to make an account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;register-account&quot;&gt;Register Account&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NestEgg web app is hosted at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.nestegg.eu&quot;&gt;my.nestegg.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the login page, &lt;a href=&quot;my.nestegg.eu/register&quot;&gt;follow the link to make a new account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following registration, you’ll receive an email to confirm your email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-your-needs&quot;&gt;Set your needs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/media/register-setkwh.png&quot; alt=&quot;Set your needs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon making successfully confirming your email address, you’ll be prompted with a question to estimate your energy needs. Once you select how many people live in your house, your self-sufficiency needs will be set and you can start reducing your energy bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to customize your energy needs further, &lt;a href=&quot;https://faq.nestegg.eu/account/dashboard/#egg-investments&quot;&gt;you can edit this in the dashboard.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">NestEgg aims to provide you the portal to crowdfund sustainable infrastructrue and reduce your basic needs by owning the production. The first step is to make an account.</summary></entry></feed>